<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arts on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/arts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arts on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:24:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe on the App Store</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze-on-the-app-store/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 16:24:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze-on-the-app-store/</guid>
      <description>CraZe is finally available on the App Store!
After lots of crazy and intense moments this year, I got enough momentum to start learning Swift from scratch, and playing around a lot with it (it is quite a nice language!).
Development started in August, and by October 80% was done, however I had to stop development for a couple months, but now I poured all my energy this last weekend into finishing the final stretch and finally publishing the first version!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>During the boredom of staying a lot at home in 2020, I got inspiration from @infrahumano to start playing around with a certain mechanism of pattern generation, outlined in his blog post (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.github.io/exterior/2020/04/04/noche.html. After that, we started a long thread in which we went along making improvements, suggestions to each other, and a lot of experimenting seeking to make these patterns look nicer. He then made a new post with such results (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Community Day, Amsterdam, 2019</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:21:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</guid>
      <description>I presented my work made on CraZe in the Processing Community Day, Amsterdam edition. It was a very interesting experience because I got to meet a booming creative coding community which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before, and because the things I presented were things I had been working on for years but had never properly presented to an audience.
 
This is the presentation I made. I got great feedback, questions, and most importantly the people I met were very inspiring because the great and curious things they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitwise Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>These are some small experiments with bitwise operations and trigonometric functions I made long time ago. The basic premise is that every pixel coordinate of the image, (i, j), is evaluated on a loop based on a formula using either bitwise operations, trigonometric functions, or a mix of both. This combination gives emergence to some surprising and very interesting patterns!
// Mod operations are also to prevent values going over 255, // because the RGB range is [0, 255].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe On The Web</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had some sort of online publicity strategy. Haven&amp;rsquo;t paid for publicity, my strategy has been very local, as in sharing stuff to my social circle, installing it myself to my friends&amp;rsquo; devices (who then install it to their friends and families), and sneakily opening it at random tech stores tablets, phones, and computers. Locally it&amp;rsquo;s a blast doing that, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale up. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been sure of how to go around trying to promote massively this kind of app in the online world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)
Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of Christmas 2012 (oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application), comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app CraZe, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought ‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>This is an animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework (but still only using the basic drawing functionality). Check out at GitHub, my homeworks for that class, mostly using Processing.
Its the language most of Computational Artists use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like hypnotic geometric GIFs, glitched art, interactive artistic installations using external hardware input, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Infinitum</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 14:15:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</guid>
      <description>A grid full of individual cells. Each with a color value chosen at random. Overall, there are 12 different colors that wrap around.
Suddenly, each cell becomes a prey, its hunter, is the &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo; color in the rules:
1 -&amp;gt; 2 / 2 -&amp;gt; 3 / n -&amp;gt; n+1 / 12 -&amp;gt; 1
If everything goes according to the plan, a curious linear and cyclical pattern is formed. But then, once in a while, rules change, and chaos appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;For all those Fractal Hearts, Convoluted, and complex.
No matter how deep, full of detail. The intrinsic shape of The Universe&amp;rdquo;

This is a simulation made in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, and fractals with neighboring initial parameters are very similar, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. You can find the code at GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>