<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:42:13 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Pt. III</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-iii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 13:42:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-iii/</guid>
      <description>You know, one thing that human society as a whole can agree with, is that 2020 has been awful, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to explain all the reasons why.
I have been &amp;ldquo;working from home&amp;rdquo; since March. Some people would think that being able to completely work from home is cool, but not necessarily. Even people who are full-time remote workers need some space and time to go out, interact with friends, go to a restaurant, go to a movie, etc, many things that given the circumstances I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to do as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>During the boredom of staying a lot at home in 2020, I got inspiration from @infrahumano to start playing around with a certain mechanism of pattern generation, outlined in his blog post (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.github.io/exterior/2020/04/04/noche.html. After that, we started a long thread in which we went along making improvements, suggestions to each other, and a lot of experimenting seeking to make these patterns look nicer. He then made a new post with such results (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 19:19:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes taken in the Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning course by the University of Alberta in Coursera, part of their Reinforcement Learning Specialization. It is a very interesting framework of learning not only because it is very game-like, but because it helps modeling the world when you want to be able learn from sequences of interactions which progressively expand the model of the world and the actors in it, differing a lot from traditional supervised and unsupervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Pt. II</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 13:42:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-ii/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Starting is easy, persistence is an art&amp;rdquo;
For a long time in my life, I just went with the flow, pursuing whatever interesting opportunities came available, but without much of an overarching goal and a plan to reach it. This direction started changing last year with this deep discussion about things seven years in the future, which planted in my head the idea of seeking an ultimate goal, or at least find such a goal for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Community Day, Amsterdam, 2019</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:21:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</guid>
      <description>I presented my work made on CraZe in the Processing Community Day, Amsterdam edition. It was a very interesting experience because I got to meet a booming creative coding community which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before, and because the things I presented were things I had been working on for years but had never properly presented to an audience.
 
This is the presentation I made. I got great feedback, questions, and most importantly the people I met were very inspiring because the great and curious things they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitwise Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>These are some small experiments with bitwise operations and trigonometric functions I made long time ago. The basic premise is that every pixel coordinate of the image, (i, j), is evaluated on a loop based on a formula using either bitwise operations, trigonometric functions, or a mix of both. This combination gives emergence to some surprising and very interesting patterns!
// Mod operations are also to prevent values going over 255, // because the RGB range is [0, 255].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seven Years Pt. I</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 13:42:13 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/seven-years-pt-i/</guid>
      <description>It was during a sort of deep talk at lunch with my teammates, that I had a deep discussion with Hadi about the future. I talked about the goals I wanted to reach, all the things I wanted to learn, but how far away or out of reach they seemed. He then told me something like
&amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s see in seven years where are you at&amp;rdquo;
It was something like a challenge and at the same time a promise, an expectation, a motivation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amsterdam, Booking.com, and Me</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/amsterdam-bookingcom-and-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/amsterdam-bookingcom-and-me/</guid>
      <description>After my second internship at Google, and the months-long very convoluted conversion process that followed with a lot of back and forth that didn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be going anywhere, I decided that it was enough and started looking for new opportunities.
I applied to many companies, but there was one that went through the whole process, and it was Booking.com.
The process was surprisingly fast, from the moment I had my on-site interviews until the moment I started working, it was only 4 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graduation</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/graduation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2016 15:15:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/graduation/</guid>
      <description>After 6 long, yet lightning fast years, I have graduated. The expected length of the Computer Science program in my university is 9 semesters, but I took an extra 3 semesters because I wanted to do a lot of stuff, specially doing several internships. It was very much worth it, and all the experiences I had while at university helped shaping who I am today. Many people in university can&amp;rsquo;t wait until going out to the &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo;, only for them to look back and think about if only they had a bit more time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Failure</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/system-failure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 02:42:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/system-failure/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;All we need to survive is one person who truly loves us&amp;rdquo;
Sometimes I forget, and then I remember. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;m aimless but then I recover my direction. The words that help me remember my purpose get lost in thoughts but then come back and I remember what I have to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe On The Web</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had some sort of online publicity strategy. Haven&amp;rsquo;t paid for publicity, my strategy has been very local, as in sharing stuff to my social circle, installing it myself to my friends&amp;rsquo; devices (who then install it to their friends and families), and sneakily opening it at random tech stores tablets, phones, and computers. Locally it&amp;rsquo;s a blast doing that, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale up. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been sure of how to go around trying to promote massively this kind of app in the online world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship(s) at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internships-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internships-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Today I got accepted for an Internship at Google this summer! This is so crazy.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on September 12th (exactly 5 months ago!), specifically because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid or unsure of applying (even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so), so I believe a personal account of my process so far (regarding applying, the interviews, process structure, etc) would be really useful and motivating for some people I know (and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)
Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of Christmas 2012 (oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application), comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app CraZe, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought ‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation Vs Discipline</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</guid>
      <description>‘Motivation may get you to take on a task or behavior that you don’t normally do but eventually that motivation will either not be there any more or won’t be effective.’
&amp;lsquo;I think many of us have a will to overcome existing habits and form new ones but we lack the way to do so. Too many distractions, too many opportunities, too many excuses.&amp;rsquo;
’Take a look at successful people around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 FIFA World Cup Memories</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 15:58:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</guid>
      <description>This is how some Germany fans from Medellín, Colombia celebrated yesterday the triumph of the Germany National Soccer Team at the 2014 FIFA World Cup! Some of these people are of German descent, others were students from the Deutsche Schule highschool (a network of schools that exists in many countries that has a focus on teaching things from the German culture and the language), and others are simply in love with the country/team, which is my case!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Device Functionality</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/exploring-device-functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/exploring-device-functionality/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with some pieces of technology (an Android Tablet, an Android Phone, Apple’s Magic Keyboard/Trackpad, a MHL-Compliant TV) which I own, and found out some simple but neat functionality which I didn’t know they could perform together:
 If you have an Android Tablet/Phone, and if you pair a BT Keyboard like Apple&amp;rsquo;s own Magic Keyboard, you can perform a lot of functionality from the keyboard. Many sites mention some basic shortcuts for external keyboards, and some seem reasonable (like the media buttons, or shortcuts to replace the regular buttons), but some are surprising because are Apple-specific buttons that perform similar functionality on an Android device, these are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KlaviKol</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 16:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</guid>
      <description>This is the most sloppy version of the intro of Muse&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;lsquo;Explorers&amp;rsquo;, played of course, by me.

This is part of my Computer Graphics class&amp;rsquo; project. It&amp;rsquo;s using the Processing programming language, the TheMidiBus library, and a KORG nanoKEY as input.
The triangle changes its size according to the pitch of the key, and the color its brighter if the key is pressed hard, if not, it will be pale in color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>This is an animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework (but still only using the basic drawing functionality). Check out at GitHub, my homeworks for that class, mostly using Processing.
Its the language most of Computational Artists use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like hypnotic geometric GIFs, glitched art, interactive artistic installations using external hardware input, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>Some members of the Veil Nebula Group at Santa Fé de Antioquia, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BlackBerry 10 Experience</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</guid>
      <description>Just today, my shiny new BlackBerry Z10 Limited Edition arrived. How did I get it? In October 2012 there were this series of events called BlackBerry Jam Sessions that were sort of a hackathon series to make apps for the new BlackBerry 10 OS platform, using either their Native SDK, the Android SDK (limited to 2.3.4) or Adobe AIR. Of course, I was interested in participating because I sorta knew how to develop for Android!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>7, 2, 1</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/7-2-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 17:27:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/7-2-1/</guid>
      <description>So, I&amp;rsquo;m fascinated by the numbers 7, 2 and 1 quite a lot. Really. Also any of the multiples of seven, but not so much as seven itself and twenty-one, and the digits of that number, two and one, and then any number with a digits combination of seven, two, and one, for example 721.
One day in school I was doing some math in my calculator, and needed the result of the 84&amp;frasl;66 fraction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Infinitum</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 14:15:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</guid>
      <description>A grid full of individual cells. Each with a color value chosen at random. Overall, there are 12 different colors that wrap around.
Suddenly, each cell becomes a prey, its hunter, is the &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo; color in the rules:
1 -&amp;gt; 2 / 2 -&amp;gt; 3 / n -&amp;gt; n+1 / 12 -&amp;gt; 1
If everything goes according to the plan, a curious linear and cyclical pattern is formed. But then, once in a while, rules change, and chaos appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
I this is a simulation in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</guid>
      <description>Some pictures I&amp;rsquo;ve taken along many years (mostly while I have been at university since 2011), years full of changes, going from thinking and doing kinda stupid stuff, to thinking and doing either kinda more rational stuff or stupider stuff heh, a whole life learning, but also, just out of pure curiosity, trying several combinations of hair styles, sometimes even cutting my own hair myself to try things. (Or sometimes experimenting odd stuff just for one day).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</guid>
      <description>2011
July 10th, 2011.  &amp;ldquo;Change everything you are, and everything you were&amp;rdquo;
September 15th, 2011.  &amp;ldquo;The circle only has one side&amp;rdquo;
October 1st, 2011.  I truly believe Echoes was made to go along 2001: A Space Odyssey.
&amp;ldquo;And no one called us to the land, and no one knows the where&amp;rsquo;s or why&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;
November 16th, 2011.  &amp;ldquo;What we&amp;rsquo;ve become, is contrary to what we want&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I work as a Software Developer in a cross-functional area at an intersection of Distributed Systems, Machine Learning, and Product Development, in which I&amp;rsquo;ve supported the simultaneous development of multiple products and initiatives, and I&amp;rsquo;ve acted as a middle point between different teams in my area and across the company, with ownership and accountability for many of these projects which have an impact on hundreds of millions of users.
My daily work involves interacting with other Developers, Data Scientists, and Product Managers, understanding their needs, and expressing mine, so that I can do my best to benefit everyone, while balancing trade-offs, and having the flexibility to be ready to experiment, improvise, or react to unforeseen situations, being aware of possible changes in the priorities of tasks and goals in a rapid changing environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>