<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>During the boredom of staying a lot at home in 2020, I got inspiration from @infrahumano to start playing around with a certain mechanism of pattern generation, outlined in his blog post (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.github.io/exterior/2020/04/04/noche.html. After that, we started a long thread in which we went along making improvements, suggestions to each other, and a lot of experimenting seeking to make these patterns look nicer. He then made a new post with such results (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Community Day, Amsterdam, 2019</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:21:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</guid>
      <description>I presented my work made on CraZe in the Processing Community Day, Amsterdam edition. It was a very interesting experience because I got to meet a booming creative coding community which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before, and because the things I presented were things I had been working on for years but had never properly presented to an audience.
 
This is the presentation I made. I got great feedback, questions, and most importantly the people I met were very inspiring because the great and curious things they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe On The Web</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had some sort of online publicity strategy. Haven&amp;rsquo;t paid for publicity, nor stormed the kind of websites where people go to show their shiny new apps and have others review it. My strategy has been very local, as in sharing stuff to my circle of contacts in Facebook, installing it myself to friends&amp;rsquo; devices (who then install it to their friends and families), or sneakily installing or opening it at random tech stores in the showcased phones and computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Today I got accepted for an Internship at Google this summer! This is so crazy.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on September 12th (exactly 5 months ago!), specifically because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid or unsure of applying (even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so), so I believe a personal account of my process so far (regarding applying, the interviews, process structure, etc) would be really useful and motivating for some people I know (and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)
Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of Christmas 2012 (oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application), comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app CraZe, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought ‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation Vs Discipline</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</guid>
      <description>‘Motivation may get you to take on a task or behavior that you don’t normally do but eventually that motivation will either not be there any more or won’t be effective.’
&amp;lsquo;I think many of us have a will to overcome existing habits and form new ones but we lack the way to do so. Too many distractions, too many opportunities, too many excuses.&amp;rsquo;
’Take a look at successful people around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 FIFA World Cup Memories</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 15:58:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</guid>
      <description>This is how some Germany fans from Medellín, Colombia celebrated yesterday the triumph of the Germany National Soccer Team at the 2014 FIFA World Cup! Some of these people are of German descent, others were students from the Deutsche Schule highschool (a network of schools that exists in many countries that has a focus on teaching things from the German culture and the language), and others are simply in love with the country/team, which is my case!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Device Functionality</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/exploring-device-functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/exploring-device-functionality/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with some pieces of technology (an Android Tablet, an Android Phone, Apple’s Magic Keyboard/Trackpad, a MHL-Compliant TV) which I own, and found out some simple but neat functionality which I didn’t know they could perform together:
 If you have an Android Tablet/Phone, and if you pair a BT Keyboard like Apple&amp;rsquo;s own Magic Keyboard, you can perform a lot of functionality from the keyboard. Many sites mention some basic shortcuts for external keyboards, and some seem reasonable (like the media buttons, or shortcuts to replace the regular buttons), but some are surprising because are Apple-specific buttons that perform similar functionality on an Android device, these are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>This is an animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework (but still only using the basic drawing functionality). Check out at GitHub, my homeworks for that class, mostly using Processing.
Its the language most of Computational Artists use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like hypnotic geometric GIFs, glitched art, interactive artistic installations using external hardware input, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would (Not)</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/i-would-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/i-would-not/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s things I’ve said I’d not want, or never do, or never be, and saw such things as negative, and nonetheless I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up wanting, doing, or becoming many of them.
‘I’d never study at ____ , such an shallow place’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never stop talking with ____ , it means a lot to me’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never put ____ before ____ , its a matter of principles’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never want to learn about ____ , or stuff related to it’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>Some members of the Veil Nebula Group at Santa Fé de Antioquia, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BlackBerry 10 Experience</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</guid>
      <description>Just today, my shiny new BlackBerry Z10 Limited Edition arrived. How did I get it? In October 2012 there were this series of events called BlackBerry Jam Sessions that were sort of a hackathon series to make apps for the new BlackBerry 10 OS platform, using either their Native SDK, the Android SDK (limited to 2.3.4) or Adobe AIR. Of course, I was interested in participating because I sorta knew how to develop for Android!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
I this is a simulation in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 0042 18:31:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</guid>
      <description>Some pictures I&amp;rsquo;ve taken along many years (mostly while I have been at university since 2011), years full of changes, going from thinking and doing kinda stupid stuff, to thinking and doing either kinda more rational stuff or stupider stuff heh, a whole life learning, but also, just out of pure curiosity, trying several combinations of hair styles, sometimes even cutting my own hair myself to try things. (Or sometimes experimenting odd stuff just for one day).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/about-me/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer Science and Engineering student from EAFIT University.
I am a person that loves learning and applying things, I believe that academia and industry growth go hand in hand, like a feedback loop. I want to seek opportunities that allow me to grow personally and intellectually, something that requires me to think and act on it. I like arts, and aesthetics, not only in the visual part, but also in things that work orderly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>