<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:05:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music Listening Analysis</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music_listening_analisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2020 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music_listening_analisis/</guid>
      <description>For years I&amp;rsquo;ve tracked the music I listen to, either my iTunes playbacks with the Last.fm scrobbler, or by listening to music on Spotify and synchronizing that with Last.fm as well.
Last.fm keeps track of all that data about songs, albums, and artists you&amp;rsquo;ve played, and there&amp;rsquo;s some nice information that they aggregate and present to you as an user. However, I wanted to do my own kind of aggregations and visualizations, but retrieving my own music listening history data seemed just too difficult as an user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KlaviKol</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 16:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</guid>
      <description>\ This is part of my Computer Graphics class&amp;rsquo; project. It&amp;rsquo;s using the Processing programming language, the TheMidiBus library, and a KORG nanoKEY as input.
The triangle changes its size according to the pitch of the key, and the color its brighter if the key is pressed hard, if not, it will be pale in color. Also, each note has its own color across the hue spectrum, going from Red to Red (mapped to musical notes, from C to C).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Infinitum</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 14:15:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</guid>
      <description>A grid full of individual cells. Each with a color value chosen at random. Overall, there are 12 different colors that wrap around.
Suddenly, each cell becomes a prey, its hunter, is the &amp;rsquo;next&amp;rsquo; color in the rules:
If everything goes according to the plan, a curious linear and cyclical pattern is formed. But then, once in a while, rules change, and chaos appears. This chaos, is the prey fighting back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>This is a simulation made in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, and fractals with neighboring initial parameters are very similar, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. You can find the code at GitHub.
The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concerts</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/concerts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/concerts/</guid>
      <description>Mago de Oz, Medellín, Plaza de Toros La Macarena, March 25th, 2006 Iron Maiden, Bogotá, Parque Simón Bolivar, February 28th, 2008 Epica, Medellín, Teatro Metropolitano, November 29th, 2009 Versailles, Bogotá, Teatro ECCI, November 9th, 2011 Miami Horror, Medellín, Discoteca Kapital, May 19th, 2013 Icona Pop, Bogotá, Royal Center, November 19th, 2014 Tame Impala, Bogotá, Royal Center, November 20th, 2014 The Lumineers, Bogotá, Royal Center, November 20th, 2014 Metronomy, Bogotá, Royal Center, November 21st, 2014 Symphony of The Goddesses, San Francisco, Davies Symphony Hall, August 29th, 2015 Foo Fighters, Mountain View, Shoreline Amphitheatre, September 16, 2015 Muse, Bogotá, Parque Deportivo 222, October 27th, 2015 The Cure, Mountain View, Shoreline Amphitheatre, May 26th, 2016 OK Go, Mountain View, Private Venue, June 30th, 2016 Distant Worlds, Houston, Jones Hall, July 23rd, 2016 Panic!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</guid>
      <description>July 10th, 2011.
September 15th, 2011.
October 1st, 2011.
November 16th, 2011.
December 1st, 2011.
December 10th, 2011.
December 18th, 2011.
December 30th, 2011.
January 2th, 2012.
February 25th, 2012.
May 27th, 2012.
June 16th, 2012.
July 9th, 2012.
July 15th, 2012.
August 30th, 2012.
September 23rd, 2012.
September 28th, 2012.
October 14th, 2012.
February 2th, 2013.
February 4th, 2013.
March 13th, 2013.
April 27th, 2013.
May 15th, 2013.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
