<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 15:10:51 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/random-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>During the boredom of staying a lot at home in 2020, I got inspiration from @infrahumano to start playing around with a certain mechanism of pattern generation, outlined in his blog post (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.github.io/exterior/2020/04/04/noche.html. After that, we started a long thread in which we went along making improvements, suggestions to each other, and a lot of experimenting seeking to make these patterns look nicer. He then made a new post with such results (in Spanish) https://infrahumano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 19:19:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes taken in the Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning course by the University of Alberta in Coursera, part of their Reinforcement Learning Specialization. It is a very interesting framework of learning not only because it is very game-like, but because it helps modeling the world when you want to be able learn from sequences of interactions which progressively expand the model of the world and the actors in it, differing a lot from traditional supervised and unsupervised learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing Community Day, Amsterdam, 2019</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 14:21:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/processing-community-day-amsterdam-2019/</guid>
      <description>I presented my work made on CraZe in the Processing Community Day, Amsterdam edition. It was a very interesting experience because I got to meet a booming creative coding community which I didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before, and because the things I presented were things I had been working on for years but had never properly presented to an audience.
 
This is the presentation I made. I got great feedback, questions, and most importantly the people I met were very inspiring because the great and curious things they do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitwise Pattern Generator</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/bitwise-pattern-generator/</guid>
      <description>These are some small experiments with bitwise operations and trigonometric functions I made long time ago. The basic premise is that every pixel coordinate of the image, (i, j), is evaluated on a loop based on a formula using either bitwise operations, trigonometric functions, or a mix of both. This combination gives emergence to some surprising and very interesting patterns!
// Mod operations are also to prevent values going over 255, // because the RGB range is [0, 255].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data-Driven Astronomy</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/data-driven-astronomy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 21:21:21 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/data-driven-astronomy/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve completed the Data-Driven Astronomy course by the University of Sydney in Coursera. It is a very interesting course because it mixes something I really like which is Astronomy, and my recently inspired interest of learning about Data Science and Machine Learning.
In Astronomy, there&amp;rsquo;s tons of data captured by multiple instruments and experiments, which is sometimes hard to parse or extract meaningful conclusions out of them by hand, which makes technologies that can process vast volumes of data and also learn from them highly valuable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe On The Web</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had some sort of online publicity strategy. Haven&amp;rsquo;t paid for publicity, my strategy has been very local, as in sharing stuff to my social circle, installing it myself to my friends&amp;rsquo; devices (who then install it to their friends and families), and sneakily opening it at random tech stores tablets, phones, and computers. Locally it&amp;rsquo;s a blast doing that, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale up. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been sure of how to go around trying to promote massively this kind of app in the online world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship(s) at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internships-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internships-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Today I got accepted for an Internship at Google this summer! This is so crazy.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on September 12th (exactly 5 months ago!), specifically because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid or unsure of applying (even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so), so I believe a personal account of my process so far (regarding applying, the interviews, process structure, etc) would be really useful and motivating for some people I know (and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)
Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of Christmas 2012 (oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application), comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app CraZe, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought ‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KlaviKol</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 16:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</guid>
      <description>This is the most sloppy version of the intro of Muse&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;lsquo;Explorers&amp;rsquo;, played of course, by me.

This is part of my Computer Graphics class&amp;rsquo; project. It&amp;rsquo;s using the Processing programming language, the TheMidiBus library, and a KORG nanoKEY as input.
The triangle changes its size according to the pitch of the key, and the color its brighter if the key is pressed hard, if not, it will be pale in color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>This is an animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework (but still only using the basic drawing functionality). Check out at GitHub, my homeworks for that class, mostly using Processing.
Its the language most of Computational Artists use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like hypnotic geometric GIFs, glitched art, interactive artistic installations using external hardware input, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BlackBerry 10 Experience</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</guid>
      <description>Just today, my shiny new BlackBerry Z10 Limited Edition arrived. How did I get it? In October 2012 there were this series of events called BlackBerry Jam Sessions that were sort of a hackathon series to make apps for the new BlackBerry 10 OS platform, using either their Native SDK, the Android SDK (limited to 2.3.4) or Adobe AIR. Of course, I was interested in participating because I sorta knew how to develop for Android!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Infinitum</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 14:15:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</guid>
      <description>A grid full of individual cells. Each with a color value chosen at random. Overall, there are 12 different colors that wrap around.
Suddenly, each cell becomes a prey, its hunter, is the &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo; color in the rules:
1 -&amp;gt; 2 / 2 -&amp;gt; 3 / n -&amp;gt; n+1 / 12 -&amp;gt; 1
If everything goes according to the plan, a curious linear and cyclical pattern is formed. But then, once in a while, rules change, and chaos appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
This is a simulation made in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, and fractals with neighboring initial parameters are very similar, so it gives the illusion that its evolving.
The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>