<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Programming on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Programming on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CraZe On The Web</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2015 03:29:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/craze_on_the_web/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never had some sort of online publicity strategy. Haven&amp;rsquo;t paid for publicity, nor stormed the kind of websites where people go to show their shiny new apps and have others review it. My strategy has been very local, as in sharing stuff to my circle of contacts in Facebook, installing it myself to friends&amp;rsquo; devices (who then install it to their friends and families), or sneakily installing or opening it at random tech stores in the showcased phones and computers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Today I got accepted for an Internship at Google this summer! This is so crazy.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on September 12th (exactly 5 months ago!), specifically because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid or unsure of applying (even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so), so I believe a personal account of my process so far (regarding applying, the interviews, process structure, etc) would be really useful and motivating for some people I know (and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)
Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of Christmas 2012 (oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application), comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app CraZe, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought ‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>This is an animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework (but still only using the basic drawing functionality). Check out at GitHub, my homeworks for that class, mostly using Processing.
Its the language most of Computational Artists use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like hypnotic geometric GIFs, glitched art, interactive artistic installations using external hardware input, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BlackBerry 10 Experience</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/the-blackberry-10-experience/</guid>
      <description>Just today, my shiny new BlackBerry Z10 Limited Edition arrived. How did I get it? In October 2012 there were this series of events called BlackBerry Jam Sessions that were sort of a hackathon series to make apps for the new BlackBerry 10 OS platform, using either their Native SDK, the Android SDK (limited to 2.3.4) or Adobe AIR. Of course, I was interested in participating because I sorta knew how to develop for Android!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
I this is a simulation in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>