<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classical Music on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/tags/classical-music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classical Music on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
    
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/tags/classical-music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2015/04/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2015/04/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hO1pn6D-t4M&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“… Shall consume the world to ashes”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral &lt;em&gt;soundtracks&lt;/em&gt; from role-playing videogames, &lt;strong&gt;when I desire to focus and not rushing things&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;When its the opposite, and I need to do things fast&lt;/strong&gt;, I listen to some upbeat electronic music, or &lt;em&gt;soundtracks&lt;/em&gt;, from either action/suspense videogames or movies, because of the feeling of urgency these cause, like time is running out, and something has to be finished before it runs out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, its a song that has both the kinda &lt;strong&gt;calm&lt;/strong&gt; classical music part, but also an &lt;strong&gt;explosive&lt;/strong&gt; beginning, it feels as an rush that lights every temper, kickstarts the brain, and then it calms down a &lt;em&gt;bit&lt;/em&gt; to make place for a bit lengthy session of focus, only to start picking up again. The same structure and feeling could be said to be delivered by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rHBG_FeITBY&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carl Orff&amp;rsquo;s Carmina Burana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening to music during a prolonged task, can be incentivating, it helps setting a rhythm, it alleviates monotomy, but I try to avoid music with much lyrics though &lt;em&gt;(at least that I can understand)&lt;/em&gt;, since listening to them draws from your attention. Thats why listening to your favorite modern band while programming can do not much good to your focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also one of my &lt;strong&gt;goals in life&lt;/strong&gt; is to live in a place where I can attend and witness such magnificent orchestras.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>