<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dies Irae</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2015 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/dies-irae/</guid>
      <description>“… Shall consume the world to ashes”
There are many kinds of music to listen while programming, sometimes I listen to some ambient sounds, or relaxed piano music, or soft vocals music, or classical music, or usually orchestral versions of soundtracks from videogames (specially role-playing games, which have a wonderful selection of music comprising many different emotions and situations), movies, or series, when I desire to focus and not rushing things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KlaviKol</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 16:06:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/klavikol/</guid>
      <description>This is the most sloppy version of the intro of Muse&amp;rsquo;s song &amp;lsquo;Explorers&amp;rsquo;, played of course, by me.

This is part of my Computer Graphics class&amp;rsquo; project. It&amp;rsquo;s using the Processing programming language, the TheMidiBus library, and a KORG nanoKEY as input.
The triangle changes its size according to the pitch of the key, and the color its brighter if the key is pressed hard, if not, it will be pale in color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ad Infinitum</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 14:15:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/ad-infinitum/</guid>
      <description>A grid full of individual cells. Each with a color value chosen at random. Overall, there are 12 different colors that wrap around.
Suddenly, each cell becomes a prey, its hunter, is the &amp;lsquo;next&amp;rsquo; color in the rules:
1 -&amp;gt; 2 / 2 -&amp;gt; 3 / n -&amp;gt; n+1 / 12 -&amp;gt; 1
If everything goes according to the plan, a curious linear and cyclical pattern is formed. But then, once in a while, rules change, and chaos appears.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
I this is a simulation in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/music/</guid>
      <description>2011
October 1st, 2011.  I truly believe Echoes was made to go along 2001: A Space Odyssey.
&amp;ldquo;And no one called us to the land, and no one knows the where&amp;rsquo;s or why&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo;
November 16th, 2011.  &amp;ldquo;What we&amp;rsquo;ve become, is contrary to what we want&amp;rdquo;
December 10th, 2011.  &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ll lay down in the sand and let the ocean lead, carry me to Innisfree like pollen on the breeze&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>