<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Science on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Science on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 19:19:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 19:19:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/fundamentals-of-reinforcement-learning/</guid>
      <description>These are my notes taken in the Fundamentals of Reinforcement Learning course by the University of Alberta in Coursera. It is a very interesting framework of learning not only because it is very game-like, but because it helps modeling the world when you want to be able learn from sequences of interactions.

At work I&amp;rsquo;ve been working as a Software Developer supporting Data Scientists in their creation of Reinforcement Learning models, they do the modelling and I work on the backend integration of such, data pipelines and cleanliness, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>Some members of the Veil Nebula Group at Santa Fé de Antioquia, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>For all those Fractal Hearts
Convoluted, and complex
No matter how deep, full of detail
The intrinsic shape of The Universe
I this is a simulation in C++ with SFML 2.0. Every frame is a Julia Set fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>