<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Apple on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/tags/apple/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Apple on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 01:32:32 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/tags/apple/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Device Functionality</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/06/exploring-device-functionality/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/06/exploring-device-functionality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with some pieces of technology &lt;em&gt;(an Android Tablet, an Android Phone, Apple’s Magic Keyboard/Trackpad, a MHL-Compliant TV)&lt;/em&gt; which I own, and found out some simple but neat functionality which I didn’t know they could perform together:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have an &lt;strong&gt;Android Tablet/Phone&lt;/strong&gt;, and if you pair a &lt;strong&gt;BT Keyboard&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s own &lt;strong&gt;Magic Keyboard&lt;/strong&gt;, you can perform a lot of functionality from the keyboard. Many sites mention some basic shortcuts for external keyboards, and some seem reasonable &lt;em&gt;(like the media buttons, or shortcuts to replace the regular buttons)&lt;/em&gt;, but some are surprising because are &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;-specific buttons that perform similar functionality on an &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; device, these are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media&lt;/strong&gt; key &lt;em&gt;(Play/Pause/Volume, which seems more reasonable).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brightness&lt;/strong&gt; key &lt;em&gt;(which usually control a Mac screen brightness, but the tablet responds to them).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exposé&lt;/strong&gt; key &lt;em&gt;(which opens up the task manager on the Android device).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Escape&lt;/strong&gt; key &lt;em&gt;(which serves as the &amp;lsquo;back&amp;rsquo; button on Android).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control + Escape&lt;/strong&gt; combo &lt;em&gt;(which serves as the &amp;lsquo;menu&amp;rsquo; button on Android).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMD + Escape&lt;/strong&gt; combo &lt;em&gt;(which serves as the &amp;lsquo;home&amp;rsquo; button on Android).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CMD + Tab&lt;/strong&gt; combo &lt;em&gt;(works like in computers, switch between open apps).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have an &lt;strong&gt;Android Tablet/Phone&lt;/strong&gt;, and if you pair a &lt;strong&gt;BT Trackpad&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;’s own &lt;strong&gt;Magic Trackpad&lt;/strong&gt;, a circular translucid cursor &lt;em&gt;(not an arrow)&lt;/em&gt; appears on screen moving along your finger on the trackpad, but also &lt;strong&gt;Multitouch Gestures&lt;/strong&gt; done on the trackpad are identified by the device &lt;em&gt;(like, every finger on the trackpad is detected, I&amp;rsquo;ve tested up to 10 fingers, all detected, and it shows one circular cursor for each finger on the trackpad as if they were on the screen)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Single Finger &amp;lsquo;Cursor&amp;rsquo;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Multiple Fingers &amp;lsquo;Cursors&amp;rsquo;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/IOv8fGX.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/IOv8fGX.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/20o2YSe.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/20o2YSe.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I think that with iOS Devices you can pair the Magic Keyboard, or any other BT Keyboard for the matter, but not the Magic Trackpad. Apple seems to be a bit allergic about having a cursor, be it arrowy or circular, on touch devices, even if its neat for TV-out and not having to be stuck in front of the TV, and their very own Magic Trackpad would allow people to perform Multi-Touch gestures from afar. Its very strange that Android devices support the full Magic Trackpad functionality, and Apple&amp;rsquo;s own iOS devices support none).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a &lt;strong&gt;MHL-Enabled TV&lt;/strong&gt;, chances are that when you connect a device like an &lt;strong&gt;Android Tablet/Phone&lt;/strong&gt; via HDMI &lt;em&gt;(I guess it counts for any device that’s MHL Compliant)&lt;/em&gt;, you can control that device using the TV’s own remove control. So, with my TV remote I can use the arrows to navigate around and also the Media Buttons &lt;em&gt;(Play/Pause/Stop)&lt;/em&gt; to control music/movies that are playing on the device, making any tablet/phone into a potential media center for the &lt;em&gt;(MHL-Enabled)&lt;/em&gt; TV without needing to buy any kind of external device to control the device from afar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats it for now, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this in case I find out any further functionality in my devices that I was not aware they could perform when I bought them, its sometimes nice to be surprised by what some pieces of technology can do!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>