<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
    
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 COT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2015/02/internship-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2015/02/internship-at-google/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I got accepted for an &lt;strong&gt;Internship&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; this summer! &lt;strong&gt;This is so crazy&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/EyYSvO6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses&lt;/strong&gt;. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on &lt;strong&gt;September 12th&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(exactly 5 months ago!)&lt;/em&gt;, particularly because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid of applying &lt;em&gt;(even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so)&lt;/em&gt;, so I believe a personal account of the process so far &lt;em&gt;(regarding applying, the interview process structure, etc)&lt;/em&gt; would be really useful and motivating for some people I know &lt;em&gt;(and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting!)&lt;/em&gt;. Of course there&amp;rsquo;s some details I can&amp;rsquo;t talk about &lt;em&gt;(like specific interview questions or other concrete details of the process)&lt;/em&gt; but in what I can talk about, I&amp;rsquo;ll try to do my best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is far from over, there&amp;rsquo;s still the &lt;strong&gt;Visa&lt;/strong&gt; thing, but as far as &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; is concerned, I got past their interviews and their project matching, which makes me really happy and optimistic for whats about to come! Once the Visa process has finalized, I&amp;rsquo;ll update this blog entry to detail very thoroughly what my experience of this whole process &lt;em&gt;(from the moment of applying to the moment of getting the visa)&lt;/em&gt; has been!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation Vs Discipline</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/11/motivation-vs-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:32:32 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/11/motivation-vs-discipline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘Motivation may get you to take on a task or behavior that you don’t normally do but eventually that motivation will either not be there any more or won’t be effective.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I think many of us have a &lt;strong&gt;will to overcome&lt;/strong&gt; existing habits and form new ones but we &lt;strong&gt;lack the way to do so&lt;/strong&gt;. Too many distractions, too many opportunities, too many excuses.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;’Take a look at successful people around you. Ask yourself are they successful because of some outside motivation or are they successful because &lt;strong&gt;they’ve made a conscious decision they’re going to wade through the muck to get what they want.&lt;/strong&gt;’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;’&lt;strong&gt;Focus&lt;/strong&gt; on being &lt;strong&gt;disciplined&lt;/strong&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;waiting&lt;/strong&gt; to be &lt;strong&gt;motivated&lt;/strong&gt;.’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reefpoints.dockyard.com/2014/10/30/motivation-vs-discipline.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ReefPoints, DockYard&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 FIFA World Cup Memories</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/07/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 15:58:35 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/07/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/knLBadgnJaw&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how some &lt;strong&gt;Germany&lt;/strong&gt; fans from &lt;strong&gt;Medellín, Colombia&lt;/strong&gt; celebrated yesterday the triumph of the &lt;strong&gt;Germany National Soccer Team&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;2014 FIFA World Cup!&lt;/strong&gt; Some of these people are of German descent, others were students from the &lt;em&gt;Deutsche Schule&lt;/em&gt; highschool &lt;em&gt;(a network of schools that exists in many countries that has a focus on teaching things from the German culture and the language)&lt;/em&gt;, and others are simply in &lt;strong&gt;love&lt;/strong&gt; with the country/team, which is my case!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people were criticizing us over &lt;em&gt;‘being fans of ~ celebrating a foreign country&amp;rsquo;s team victory’&lt;/em&gt;, but let me tell them, &lt;strong&gt;FUCK YOU :-D&lt;/strong&gt; Soccer is for entertainment, not about forced loyalty to a certain nation or continent. We did support the &lt;strong&gt;Colombian National Soccer Team&lt;/strong&gt; while it was still running, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we couldn&amp;rsquo;t support and appreciate the beast of a team the Germans are!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the people criticizing us argued that we should have supported the &lt;strong&gt;Argentinians&lt;/strong&gt; at the final match, because they were our &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;latin brothers&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Others criticized that we were just &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;tagging along in the victory/hype train&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; because we were celebrating another country&amp;rsquo;s triumph. &lt;strong&gt;Well, the triumph is ours to celebrate, all fans, no matter the country!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dLAIjbJvx7s&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, moving into &lt;em&gt;more important matters&lt;/em&gt;, The &lt;strong&gt;Colombian National Soccer Team&lt;/strong&gt; had an impressive, unprecedented display at the cup! &lt;strong&gt;It was beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;. Everyone was engaged to following the matches, they had huge live screens in every shopping mall, restaurants everywhere were crowded because of their promos for the matches &lt;em&gt;(and even had thematic decorations)&lt;/em&gt;, several brands had campaigns involving discounts one way or another regarding the matches &lt;em&gt;(like, I bought a really cool TV because of those promotions)&lt;/em&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t usually follow soccer, heck, I don&amp;rsquo;t even see any match between clubs, not even those &lt;em&gt;European Leagues&lt;/em&gt; a lot of people is usually crazy about. &lt;strong&gt;Soccer is usually never on my mind, unless its a World Cup&lt;/strong&gt;, thats the brief period of time every 4 years where the whole craziness ensued by a worldwide congregation of teams and cultures really drags me into following the whole thing and feeling the whole excitement. Thats what I love about World Cups, the cultures clashing, people in a country mostly supporting a team &lt;em&gt;(instead of petty rivalries between clubs from the same country or city, which sadly in some cases leads to nonsense violence)&lt;/em&gt;, the fans that travel huge distances, and of course, &lt;strong&gt;watching the best players from everywhere!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; golden team (1980~1998)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The &amp;lsquo;new&amp;rsquo; golden team (2012~2014)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/2dAdqfG.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/GK0ks0V.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there were several special reasons for us to be hyped beyond reason for our national team. First, it had been like &lt;strong&gt;16 years&lt;/strong&gt; since the last World Cup we attended &lt;em&gt;(France 1998, I think).&lt;/em&gt; The early 90&amp;rsquo;s were kind of a &lt;strong&gt;Golden Era&lt;/strong&gt; of soccer in Colombia, with many world-class luminaries, most notably the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Carlos_Valderrama&#34;&gt;Pibe Valderrama&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ren%C3%A9_Higuita&#34;&gt;Rene Higuita&lt;/a&gt;, but such golden times gradually faded away, and many fans and players alike, got stuck inside the memories of past glories. The &lt;strong&gt;2000&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; came, and even though some really good players came around, these were more like &lt;em&gt;hits and misses&lt;/em&gt;, without enough cohesion and proper coaching for assembling a solid country team. It was as if &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;every man for himself&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; was a norm with everyone wanting to be the star, and instead of building cohesive teams, the national team served almost just for showcasing players abroad and getting foreign clubs into buying them. It was a fine decade for individual player performances and some club performances &lt;em&gt;(like Once Caldas winning the Libertadores Cup)&lt;/em&gt;, but the national team did very poor on a constant basis. Also during the whole decade many people still lived under the shadow of past glories, instead of looking up to live again up to that. For example, every year people keeps remembering the &lt;strong&gt;5-0 victory against Argentina&lt;/strong&gt;, just a match in a qualifier round, which happened in &lt;strong&gt;1993&lt;/strong&gt; and people celebrate it as if it was a World Cup victory, and keep talking a lot about it, as if it was yesterday, &lt;em&gt;almost 20 years later&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Colombia&amp;rsquo;s National Team Constantly Changing Coaches&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1gWZzcq.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing in that disorderly behavior, were the &lt;strong&gt;coaches&lt;/strong&gt;. They were constantly being swapped around because of their poor performances, without enough time to develop a long term vision. Like, some of the coaches just lasted one ~ two years, some even a few months, if not less, and &lt;strong&gt;nobody can expect to have a solid team when your coach leaves as soon as it arrived&lt;/strong&gt;. Changing a coach is changing a vision, a structure, a way of management, a set of disciplines, a way of work. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there, not only were they &lt;em&gt;changing coaches like clothing&lt;/em&gt;, but they reached a point were they &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;didn&amp;rsquo;t know who else to call&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; so they tried again with some of these coaches, resulting in not only having poor coaches, lasting for relatively brief periods of time, but also trying some again, and again, and again, thinking the results would be different. &lt;strong&gt;Its like someone getting back with their exes after a bad relationship end, hoping now things would be better, just because they once were&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one can deny some of these coaches were good &lt;em&gt;time ago&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;but those times were like a decade or two ago&lt;/strong&gt;, and now they were being called hoping they would repeat their long gone success, just because &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;tradition&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;keeping it inside the family (country)&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;with the fear of looking outside for a capable and focused coach&lt;/strong&gt;, devoid of any of those feelings of &lt;strong&gt;clinging to past glory&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(the reasons to keep it only Colombians and repeating the same old people was a mix between nationalism and being stuck in the memories of when those coaches were relatively good, ignoring their present awful management)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not unusual for a country&amp;rsquo;s national team to have a foreigner as coach, in fact, Colombia&amp;rsquo;s national team has had several foreign coaches, but the last one was like &lt;strong&gt;30~40 years ago&lt;/strong&gt;. Since then, all the coaches at the national team have been Colombians, and when &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jos%C3%A9_P%C3%A9kerman&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;José Pékerman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, an Argentinian, was announced as the new coach in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt;, many of the &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;traditional&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; coaches, and even some fans, went into an uproar, saying that &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;the coach should be from Colombia&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt; and that &lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;there&amp;rsquo;s plenty of capable Colombian coaches to lead the national team&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Well, if there were, why were we cycling between some average, and some really burnt out coaches, over and over and over again, almost on a yearly basis, during 10+ years, without any signs of progress whatsoever?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/GESyL3MkgNU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then the &lt;strong&gt;2010&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt; came around, and not only several rising stars started to appear &lt;em&gt;(not just hits and misses, but people to build a solid team around)&lt;/em&gt;, but in &lt;strong&gt;2012&lt;/strong&gt; came the arrival of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jos%C3%A9_P%C3%A9kerman&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pékerman&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; who in his strictness &lt;em&gt;(and being devoid of any of those sensations of clinging to decades-old glories)&lt;/em&gt; built a very solid foundation for what came the &lt;strong&gt;New Golden Generation&lt;/strong&gt; of the national team, which made it to the World Cup for the first time in 16 years, made it 2nd in the qualifiers in the continent, became one of eigth &lt;em&gt;Group Heads&lt;/em&gt; for the team drawings, was one of the few teams that made it through the &lt;em&gt;Group Phase&lt;/em&gt; winning all matches and the second team scoring the most goals in the phase, and for the first time in Colombian history, made it past the &lt;em&gt;Round of 16&lt;/em&gt;, had a player (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/James_Rodr%C3%ADguez&#34;&gt;James Rodriguez&lt;/a&gt;) winning the &lt;strong&gt;Golden Boot&lt;/strong&gt; for most goals scored, and also the &lt;strong&gt;Best Goal Award&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(and what a beautiful one!)&lt;/em&gt;, and ending up 3rd in the &lt;strong&gt;FIFA World Ranking&lt;/strong&gt;, which was an impressive feat, considering we didn&amp;rsquo;t make it past quarter finals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides Rodriguez, another really good player during the qualifiers was &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Radamel_Falcao&#34;&gt;Falcao Garcia&lt;/a&gt;, who was a key striker during the process, but got a untimely injury just months before the cup started &lt;em&gt;(but the team had already qualified by then)&lt;/em&gt;, which left him out of the picture, and still, the team did &lt;strong&gt;wonders&lt;/strong&gt; in those few months to rearrange itself and accomodate to his absence, which really talks good about the flexibility the national selection has, and the mastery ~ leadership that the coach has on the team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For me the World Cup was the best thing from 2014, I shared many good times with my friends and family because of it, and its a memory I&amp;rsquo;ll cherish in my heart for as long as I can!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would (Not)</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2013/12/i-would-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 02:19:23 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2013/12/i-would-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s things I’ve said &lt;strong&gt;I’d not want&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;never do&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;never be&lt;/strong&gt;, and saw such things as negative, and nonetheless I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up &lt;strong&gt;wanting&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;doing&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;becoming&lt;/strong&gt; many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; study at ____ , such an shallow place’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; stop talking with ____ , it means a lot to me’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; put ____ before ____ , its a matter of principles’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; want to learn about ____ , or stuff related to it’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; become like ____ , it gets on my nerves&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; dedicate myself to ____, such an meaningless way of life&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; like anyone that isn&amp;rsquo;t ____&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And many others mental statements like that&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the things I’ve wanted to pursue, or thought to myself that I must want, do, or become, which are the things I ended up myself achieving the less, or not at all. For some reason it was apparently more probable for me to get to something I say I must not, or rather not, than getting to something I say I must or I want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I came to the realization that some of the things I’ve said &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;not’&lt;/strong&gt; to before, were part of how I really was, or am, things I had forgotten that were part of what defined myself, but no matter how much I tried fighting against them, I&amp;rsquo;d end up drawn back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such thoughts, lifestyles, ways of acting and doing things, &lt;strong&gt;that were the most like myself&lt;/strong&gt;, started being eroded away by some &lt;strong&gt;external pressures&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(such as being labeled an outcast, and also the fear of not living up to the expectations many people has in myself)&lt;/em&gt;, some stupid or broken &lt;strong&gt;moral or social imperatives&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(like, you must be this way if you ever want to amount to anything)&lt;/em&gt;, and some stupid desire of &lt;strong&gt;wanting to live the lives of others and not my own&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(as in, trying to live, act and work the way the people I admired lived, acted and worked, because I thought that by doing so I&amp;rsquo;d achieve the success for which I admired them, that it would be easier following their trail, rather than making my own path)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I&amp;rsquo;d always find really hard to adapt myself to such things I and mistakenly saw as &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt;, then feeling bad because of such failed attempts, and then being drawn back with an inmense force to the things I mistakenly saw as &lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;/strong&gt;, but weren&amp;rsquo;t bad, just were the things most like me, that I forced myself to see as bad just trying to fit in, live up to the expectations of others, and living the lives of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The solution of these issues can come down to, trying to ignore the most obnoxious broken moral or social imperatives&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(self-fulfillment, at the cost of possibly not being what others and society defines as good, or acceptable)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;trying to be and live with who you are&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(not shaping your life to the lives of others, their ideas of success or what they perceive as good or acceptable)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;and not trying to be and live up to what others want you to be and live up to&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(not shaping your life according to the pressure coming from their expectations, living up to what you, and not others, want of yourself)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2013/07/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2013/07/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/qGrN3pb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/qLxMe9G.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some members of the &lt;strong&gt;Veil Nebula Group&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Fe_de_Antioquia&#34;&gt;Santa Fé de Antioquia&lt;/a&gt;, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Milky Way&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t appear in a regular photo though, These are 5~8 second long exposure photos, but the sky was the clearest I’ve seen in my life, and the galaxy plus several hard to catch constellations were quite noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Veil Nebula Group&lt;/strong&gt; is an amateur astronomy group I&amp;rsquo;m no longer part of, we had fun times, hanged out, talked about the stars &lt;em&gt;(very scientifically, it was not only observational)&lt;/em&gt;, some of us were young &lt;em&gt;(and still in university)&lt;/em&gt;, the directors were older &lt;em&gt;(but wiser)&lt;/em&gt; folks who sometimes invited their families, but in the end some of the original members &lt;em&gt;(mostly we the young ones, still in university)&lt;/em&gt; left because of many reasons &lt;em&gt;(mostly academic)&lt;/em&gt;. Still, I hold the memories of our experiences in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.495337, -75.804441&lt;/strong&gt; in case you want to send a missile, go to watch the stars, or something else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>