<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Internship at Google</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2015 15:49:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/internship-at-google/</guid>
      <description>Today I got accepted for an Internship at Google this summer! This is so crazy.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet come back to my senses. There&amp;rsquo;s so much I want to write regarding this, mostly about the process so far, which started on September 12th (exactly 5 months ago!), specifically because there&amp;rsquo;s some people in my university afraid or unsure of applying (even if university recruiters try to motivate people to do so), so I believe a personal account of my process so far (regarding applying, the interviews, process structure, etc) would be really useful and motivating for some people I know (and perhaps some others I don&amp;rsquo;t, which still may find this interesting).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motivation Vs Discipline</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 01:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/motivation-vs-discipline/</guid>
      <description>‘Motivation may get you to take on a task or behavior that you don’t normally do but eventually that motivation will either not be there any more or won’t be effective.’
&amp;lsquo;I think many of us have a will to overcome existing habits and form new ones but we lack the way to do so. Too many distractions, too many opportunities, too many excuses.&amp;rsquo;
’Take a look at successful people around you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2014 FIFA World Cup Memories</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 15:58:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2014-fifa-world-cup-memories/</guid>
      <description>This is how some Germany fans from Medellín, Colombia celebrated yesterday the triumph of the Germany National Soccer Team at the 2014 FIFA World Cup! Some of these people are of German descent, others were students from the Deutsche Schule highschool (a network of schools that exists in many countries that has a focus on teaching things from the German culture and the language), and others are simply in love with the country/team, which is my case!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would (Not)</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/i-would-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/i-would-not/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s things I’ve said I’d not want, or never do, or never be, and saw such things as negative, and nonetheless I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up wanting, doing, or becoming many of them.
‘I’d never study at ____ , such an shallow place’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never stop talking with ____ , it means a lot to me’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never put ____ before ____ , its a matter of principles’
&amp;lsquo;I’d never want to learn about ____ , or stuff related to it’</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>Some members of the Veil Nebula Group at Santa Fé de Antioquia, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changes</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 0042 18:31:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/changes/</guid>
      <description>Some pictures I&amp;rsquo;ve taken along many years (mostly while I have been at university since 2011), years full of changes, going from thinking and doing kinda stupid stuff, to thinking and doing either kinda more rational stuff or stupider stuff heh, a whole life learning, but also, just out of pure curiosity, trying several combinations of hair styles, sometimes even cutting my own hair myself to try things. (Or sometimes experimenting odd stuff just for one day).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>