<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/about/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/categories/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/42/06/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 0042 14:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/42/06/about-me/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a &lt;em&gt;Computer Science and Engineering&lt;/em&gt; student at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eafit.edu.co&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EAFIT University&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to learn &lt;strong&gt;AND&lt;/strong&gt; do a lot of stuff!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to experiment with a lot of crazy stuff, mixing both technology and science in a way that results both fun, insightful and productive! Without going too deep into academics, nor just doing a technical labor, I want to grow both in the knowledge and the application of what I love, because I strongly believe that both education and work should go hand in hand, as both feed from the other positively in incredible ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also love arts, from time to time drawing by hand and playing around with code that generastes artsy, colorful stuff, involving concepts of geometry, trigonometry, linear algebra, and other math constructs such as fractals and repeating patterns. But its more than a love for artsy stuff, its a feeling of pursuing aesthetics, that I try to make present in everything I do, as there are many forms of beauty, there is beauty in visually appealing things, there is beauty in things that are simple and work well, there is beauty in things that are ordered, there is beauty in things that work together like clockwork to achieve a common goal, etc. Thats my love of art, love of beauty, that can be applied together with the sciences to make nice things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As hobbies, I like riding a bicycle, taking a lot of &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/zubie7a&#34;&gt;pictures&lt;/a&gt;, eating pizza, and binge-watching lots of series and &lt;a href=&#34;http://thefuckingmovies.tumblr.com&#34;&gt;movies&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my programming work is regarding &lt;strong&gt;Web Backends&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Distributed Systems&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Information Security&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Data Structures and Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;, but in my free time I explore things related to &lt;strong&gt;Computational Art&lt;/strong&gt;, regarding this I made for fun a drawing app for making designs with effects, rotations, symmetry, and brushes which is available at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zubieta.craze&#34;&gt;Android Play Store&lt;/a&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s also a multiuser &lt;a href=&#34;http://craze.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;Chrome version&lt;/a&gt; and sometimes I &lt;a href=&#34;http://instagram.com/crazeapp&#34;&gt;post images&lt;/a&gt; made with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whats in a name?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The namesake of this blog, &lt;strong&gt;Z10Z&lt;/strong&gt;, is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Numeronym&#34;&gt;numeronym&lt;/a&gt;, created with my two last names :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>