<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Realizations on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/tags/realizations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Realizations on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 02:19:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/tags/realizations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I Would (Not)</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2013/12/i-would-not/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2013 02:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2013/12/i-would-not/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s things I’ve said &lt;strong&gt;I’d not want&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;never do&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;never be&lt;/strong&gt;, and saw such things as negative, and nonetheless I&amp;rsquo;ve ended up &lt;strong&gt;wanting&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;doing&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;becoming&lt;/strong&gt; many of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; study at &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; , such an shallow place’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; stop talking with &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; , it means a lot to me’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; put &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; before &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; , its a matter of principles’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; want to learn about &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; , or stuff related to it’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I’d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; become like &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt; , it gets on my nerves&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; dedicate myself to &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;, such an meaningless way of life&amp;rsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;lsquo;I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;strong&gt;never&lt;/strong&gt; like anyone that isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;code&gt;____&lt;/code&gt;&amp;lsquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And many others mental statements like that&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there&amp;rsquo;s the things I’ve wanted to pursue, or thought to myself that I must want, do, or become, which are the things I ended up myself achieving the less, or not at all. For some reason it was apparently more probable for me to get to do something I say I must not do, or rather not do, than getting to something I say I must do or I want to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I came to the realization that some of the things I’ve said &lt;strong&gt;&amp;lsquo;not’&lt;/strong&gt; to do before, were part of how I really was, or am, things I had forgotten that were part of what defined myself, but no matter how much I tried fighting against them, I&amp;rsquo;d end up drawn back to them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such thoughts, lifestyles, ways of acting and doing things, &lt;strong&gt;that were the most like myself&lt;/strong&gt;, started being eroded away by some &lt;strong&gt;external pressures&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(such as being labeled an outcast, and also the fear of not living up to the expectations many people has in myself)&lt;/em&gt;, some stupid or broken &lt;strong&gt;moral or social imperatives&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(like, you must be this way if you ever want to amount to anything)&lt;/em&gt;, and some stupid desire of &lt;strong&gt;wanting to live the lives of others and not my own&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(as in, trying to live, act and work the way the people I admired lived, acted and worked, because I thought that by doing so I&amp;rsquo;d achieve the success for which I admired them, that it would be easier following their trail, rather than making my own path)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I&amp;rsquo;d always find really hard to adapt myself to such things I and mistakenly saw as &lt;strong&gt;good&lt;/strong&gt;, then feeling bad because of such failed attempts, and then being drawn back with an inmense force to the things I mistakenly saw as &lt;strong&gt;bad&lt;/strong&gt;, but weren&amp;rsquo;t bad, just were the things most like me, that I forced myself to see as bad just trying to fit in, live up to the expectations of others, and living the lives of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The solution of these issues can come down to, trying to ignore the most obnoxious broken moral or social imperatives&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(self-fulfillment, at the cost of possibly not being what others and society defines as good, or acceptable)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;trying to be and live with who you are&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(not shaping your life to the lives of others, their ideas of success or what they perceive as good or acceptable)&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;and not trying to be and live up to what others want you to be and live up to&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(not shaping your life according to the pressure coming from their expectations, living up to what you, and not others, want of yourself)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>