<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blackberry on Z10Z</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/z10z/tags/blackberry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blackberry on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/z10z/tags/blackberry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The BlackBerry 10 Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/z10z/2013/03/the-blackberry-10-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2013 21:46:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/z10z/2013/03/the-blackberry-10-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://31.media.tumblr.com/fa225f37defd8d02809642a740ce939c/tumblr_inline_mkalo96N9X1qz4rgp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just today, my shiny new &lt;strong&gt;BlackBerry Z10&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Limited Edition&lt;/em&gt; arrived. How did I get it? In &lt;strong&gt;October 2012&lt;/strong&gt; there were this series of events called &lt;strong&gt;BlackBerry Jam Sessions&lt;/strong&gt; that were sort of a &lt;strong&gt;hackathon&lt;/strong&gt; series to make apps for the new &lt;strong&gt;BlackBerry 10 OS&lt;/strong&gt; platform, using either their &lt;strong&gt;Native SDK&lt;/strong&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;Android SDK&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(limited to 2.3.4)&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Adobe AIR&lt;/strong&gt;. Of course, I was interested in participating because I sorta knew how to develop for &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Just as a note, the blog&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Z10Z&lt;/strong&gt; name is absolutely unrelated to the &lt;strong&gt;Z10&lt;/strong&gt; name of the phone)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the platform overall is nice, but I believe it came &lt;strong&gt;too late&lt;/strong&gt;. BlackBerry took too long to get into the touchscreen smartphone market, with several monthly, or even yearly delays. They were kings with the physical keyboard models that predated current smartphones &lt;em&gt;(everyone I knew were crazy about these)&lt;/em&gt; but were slowly phased out and forgotten by the incoming wave of &lt;strong&gt;Apple&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; and even &lt;strong&gt;Windows&lt;/strong&gt; smartphones, being relegated to the corporate environment, and even there being replaced by this new technologies. In the end they came new to a place were others were already very mature, without bringing much new stuff, and requiring people to develop for yet another platform, so in my opinion they should have become a complete fork of &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; and support immediately its full, huge application base, instead of giving limited support with some porting tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anyway, lets talk about the hackathon!&lt;/strong&gt; In our team we developed an app for helping children and adolescents learn formulas from several &lt;em&gt;mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;geometry&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;chemistry&lt;/em&gt; and other &lt;em&gt;sciences&lt;/em&gt; topics, by inputting values into visual representations of whatever a formula was about, and finding the missing values, together with an explanation of such formulas. I was in charge of the software design and programming of the app, and putting together its visual interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some friends did the gathering of resources &lt;em&gt;(images, formulas)&lt;/em&gt;, others did the pitch &lt;em&gt;(all the talk about how it worked, the idea, the business model, guided by an awesomely crafted presentation)&lt;/em&gt; and I did the coding and visual structuring. In the end, we won the &lt;strong&gt;Best Application Design&lt;/strong&gt; award!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/glK0UQA.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were 5 awards, each one with a trophy, and a backpack. The Best App award took home a Playbook, which I think they sold, because well, selling it and dividing cash is better than arguing who should keep the tablet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it didn’t stop there! They gave every contestant a &lt;strong&gt;Blackberry Dev Alpha B&lt;/strong&gt; unit, with the promise that if people had an app developed and approved into the &lt;strong&gt;Blackberry App World&lt;/strong&gt; before January 21st &lt;em&gt;(later extended until February 28th)&lt;/em&gt; they would qualify for exchanging the &lt;strong&gt;Dev Alpha B&lt;/strong&gt; unit for a &lt;strong&gt;Red Limited Edition&lt;/strong&gt; version of the finished &lt;em&gt;(retail)&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Z10&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Boot Screen&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unfinished Body&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/AVi71zz.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/lbIpY8i.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application I had submitted was a port of the &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; version of &lt;a href=&#34;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.zubieta.craze&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CraZe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;! But I was kinda sad because at the day of the contest they didn’t say anything about the application submitted having to be one per person, I thought it would suffice for everyone in the team to exchange their &lt;strong&gt;Dev Alpha B&lt;/strong&gt; for the &lt;strong&gt;Z10&lt;/strong&gt;, so some people were unable to submit and get an application approved by the store and got stuck with the beta phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/C76Lxom.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1048 out of 12000 ever made!&lt;/strong&gt; Many were eager to sell the phone, I won&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;(even though I won&amp;rsquo;t use it for the foreseeable future because I have a new Galaxy S3)&lt;/em&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ll keep it as some crown of achievement!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/wp0C6Sa.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/oV26fT4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/X36dl2e.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/TK5NjX9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>