<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astronomy on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/tags/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astronomy on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/tags/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Those Starry Nights</title>
      <link>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2013/07/those-starry-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 19:19:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubie7a.github.io/z10z/2013/07/those-starry-nights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/qGrN3pb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/qLxMe9G.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some members of the &lt;strong&gt;Veil Nebula Group&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Santa_Fe_de_Antioquia&#34;&gt;Santa Fé de Antioquia&lt;/a&gt;, or at least close to there. Its a very colonial town with mountains close to it, where several people have vacation houses. One particular thing about the place is that since its a small town and far from the main cities, there are no city lights in several dozens of kilometers, so the sky is kinda nice for amateur astronomy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Milky Way&lt;/strong&gt; won&amp;rsquo;t appear in a regular photo though, These are 5~8 second long exposure photos, but the sky was the clearest I’ve seen in my life, and the galaxy plus several hard to catch constellations were quite noticeable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Veil Nebula Group&lt;/strong&gt; is an amateur astronomy group I&amp;rsquo;m no longer part of, we had fun times, hanged out, talked about the stars &lt;em&gt;(very scientifically, it was not only observational)&lt;/em&gt;, some of us were young &lt;em&gt;(and still in university)&lt;/em&gt;, the directors were older &lt;em&gt;(but wiser)&lt;/em&gt; folks who sometimes invited their families, but in the end some of the original members &lt;em&gt;(mostly we the young ones, still in university)&lt;/em&gt; left because of many reasons &lt;em&gt;(mostly study)&lt;/em&gt;. Still, I hold very dear the memories of our experiences in my heart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.495337, -75.804441&lt;/strong&gt; in case you want to send a missile, go to watch the stars, or something else.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>