<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Arts on Z10Z</title>
    <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/categories/arts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Arts on Z10Z</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
    
    
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 COT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/categories/arts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays of CraZe Times</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/12/holidays-of-craze-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2014 21:46:47 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/12/holidays-of-craze-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://imgur.com/a/VxwIm&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/lMDyHG9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Click the image to go to a web album containing several drawings that some people and myself have made with the application)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like a long forgotten promise, from the depths of &lt;strong&gt;Christmas 2012&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(oh, that weekend of the 7th~9th when I first did the web application)&lt;/em&gt;, comes a brief resurrection of my psychedelic drawing app &lt;a href=&#34;https://craze.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CraZe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, because I once promised myself that I’d make it multi-user ~ concurrent, but jokingly thought &lt;em&gt;‘nah, seems very hard to accomplish such a thing, maybe in 90 years’&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;That promise has come true, 88 years earlier than expected heh.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, &lt;strong&gt;Christmas&lt;/strong&gt; vacations is usually a period where I tend to stay idle for long times, even weeks, reminiscing about the year that has just passed, what did I achieve &lt;em&gt;(or not)&lt;/em&gt;, how much of my goals went through, or if I adquired new goals. Then feeling &lt;strong&gt;sad&lt;/strong&gt;, feeling &lt;strong&gt;happy&lt;/strong&gt;, feeling &lt;strong&gt;nostalgic&lt;/strong&gt; of when I was a kid and past Christmasses, and mostly, &lt;strong&gt;having no idea of what to do with my free time&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(perhaps having way too much ideas on what to do or what to learn but being too indecisive to follow through any of them because of the feeling of missing out on the others)&lt;/em&gt; but then I start resolving to do some things, and dedicate myself for days non-stop on them and &lt;strong&gt;feel really good&lt;/strong&gt; because of it, because its having full time to do what I want, completely free from university obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, its &lt;strong&gt;Christmas 2014&lt;/strong&gt;, and I spent most of it laying idle being too indecisive on what to do, but then I resolved to learn some further &lt;strong&gt;NodeJS&lt;/strong&gt; stuff yesterday, and while reading about &lt;a href=&#34;http://socket.io&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SocketIO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, which enables easy realtime communication between app frontend instances and a backend, I remembered that old promise about making my app multi-user ~ concurrent, and then kept reading all that morning and afternoon about it, which sufficed for spending the whole night and next morning bringing the project back from the land of the long-dead-code &lt;em&gt;(god my code styling and structuring was nefarious back then, two years ago)&lt;/em&gt;, and successfully adapted it for such simultaneous drawing purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For using the updated functionality, you enter an initial &lt;strong&gt;Room&lt;/strong&gt; called &lt;strong&gt;Lobby&lt;/strong&gt;, with a predefined &lt;strong&gt;Guest&lt;/strong&gt; username, the settings are at the right as usual, but now you have a row of buttons at the bottom, to &lt;strong&gt;check the users&lt;/strong&gt; in your same room, to &lt;strong&gt;join another room&lt;/strong&gt;, or to &lt;strong&gt;change your nickname&lt;/strong&gt;. It draws every line, every point, that other users in the same room draw, in real time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, someone told me that hosting at &lt;strong&gt;Heroku&lt;/strong&gt; made things run a bit sluggish, but in my opinion its a good free hosting that provides backend functionality &lt;em&gt;(that is not PHP)&lt;/em&gt;, and very easy to deploy to, all of which fulfills my basic needs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the code at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Zubieta/CraZe_Web&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and make sure you &lt;a href=&#34;https://craze.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;have a nice time drawing with it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing With Processing</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/02/playing-with-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2014 02:19:23 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2014/02/playing-with-processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;420&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a2qDobiht7g&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(An animation I did for a Computer Graphics class homework, without using any of the built in 2D/3D cartesian transformations, but the ones taught to us at class after I garnered some experience by playing around with the framework. Check out at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Zubieta/Computer_Graphics&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, my homeworks for that class, mostly using &lt;strong&gt;Processing&lt;/strong&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its the language most of &lt;strong&gt;Computational Artists&lt;/strong&gt; use nowadays to make some neat stuff, like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/search/processing+gif&#34;&gt;hypnotic geometric GIFs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/search/processing+glitch&#34;&gt;glitched art&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OGoZktCzMS4&#34;&gt;interactive artistic installations&lt;/a&gt; using external hardware input, etc. See for yourself some &lt;a href=&#34;https://processing.org/exhibition/&#34;&gt;crazy stuff done with it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I couldn’t initially resist the temptation of playing around with some images’ pixels like a lot of cool kids do nowadays, as some way of initially testing the framework capabilities or basic functionality. I tried making an &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; camera thing with filters, then it glitched terribly, then I thought of playing for now just with some old images and glitching them, but now I want to make an &lt;strong&gt;Android Glitch/Artsy Camera&lt;/strong&gt; app! Instagram better watch their backs&amp;hellip; or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are kind of the most noteworthy images among a bunch of not good looking mishaps &lt;em&gt;(glitch art is supposed to be about mishaps, but even among glitched images there are some artsy and some plainly awful)&lt;/em&gt;. Some of these could be done very easily with enough photoshop knowledge, but hell, its programming! Also, because I was changing stuff almost randomly or without a set goal &lt;em&gt;(or without knowing what would it even do)&lt;/em&gt; I have no code to recreate any of these, but it shouldn’t be that hard to recreate for anyone not so inexperienced as I kinda am now! &lt;strong&gt;All these were done with direct pixel manipulation, and the use of crazy bitwise operations, formulas based on RGB value, and loops.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/uK99OCH.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/uK99OCH.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/8pGEv3u.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/8pGEv3u.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/I7UAuy9.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/I7UAuy9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/SBoNneC.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/SBoNneC.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1x9EkUl.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/1x9EkUl.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/WaqbgcQ.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/WaqbgcQ.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/NPCJnXH.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/NPCJnXH.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/rAP7ERq.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/rAP7ERq.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/w2R0RBx.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgur.com/w2R0RBx.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/jsJh4jm.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/jsJh4jm.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/J5NWF9I.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/J5NWF9I.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/WyQEtNq.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/WyQEtNq.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processing&lt;/strong&gt; is awesome, it is built on top on &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; but at the same time its &lt;strong&gt;damn fast&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(and faster if you are using low-level stuff)&lt;/em&gt;, and allows exporting to &lt;strong&gt;Android&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Javascript&lt;/strong&gt; with no changes to the code &lt;em&gt;(if you are using nothing more than the default bindings and libraries, no platform specific stuff)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has its &lt;strong&gt;own IDE&lt;/strong&gt;, the basic idea of is that if you are going to work with the raw &lt;strong&gt;Processing&lt;/strong&gt; language, you can export the working app to other platforms without making any changes to the code, the IDE handles that, but at the cost that you can&amp;rsquo;t use any existing library that is specific to any of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also makes a lot easier to manage &lt;strong&gt;input events&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(mouse, keyboard, external sensors/devices)&lt;/em&gt; without dealing yourself with the management of threads &lt;em&gt;(it basically seems to have a thread for managing such events, and another which continously draws the window, perfect for interactive non-blocking stuff)&lt;/em&gt;. It also has great bindings to &lt;strong&gt;graphic/geometric functions and transformations&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you can also develop in &lt;strong&gt;Eclipse&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;(which is painful at first, having to extract the core .jar libraries from Processing and add them to your new projects manually every time)&lt;/em&gt;, but once you get the grasp of it, its awesome, because how easy it becomes to use external &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; packages, debuggers, and other tools, or manually include the &lt;strong&gt;Processing.js&lt;/strong&gt; files in a web page project and develop directly in HTML/JS with some of its bindings &lt;em&gt;(at the cost of missing cross-compatibility).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in &lt;strong&gt;Eclipse&lt;/strong&gt; you can sacrifice that for nice code completion, debugging, tons of existing libraries, and faster time to run &lt;em&gt;(its a ton faster to deploy an Android app from PC to device in Eclipse than from Processing’s IDE)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shine On You Crazy Fractal</title>
      <link>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2012/05/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2012 02:19:23 COT</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zubieta.github.io/z10z/2012/05/shine-on-you-crazy-fractal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/-Lhw-qdXUis&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For all those Fractal Hearts&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Convoluted, and complex&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;No matter how deep, full of detail&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The intrinsic shape of The Universe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I this is a simulation in &lt;strong&gt;C++&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;SFML 2.0&lt;/strong&gt;. Every frame is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Julia_set&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Julia Set&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; fractal rendered with a slightly varying initial parameter, so it gives the illusion that its evolving. The first strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a row by row scan of points of the complex plane from the uppermost left corner down the the lowermost right corner. The second strategy for varying the initial parameter is like a spiral that starts at the center of the complex plane and starts spiralling out from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when I watch this video, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but notice how it continously cycles from two separate main bodies into a single one and viceversa. It looks as if two galaxies were dancing around each other, merging, and separating, and merging, and separating. The dynamics of galaxy collissions shows that when they are on a collision course, they sort of dance around each other, then go through each other, then separate, then go across each other again, until their cores merge and stabilize. &lt;strong&gt;Luckily for fractals, their dance can go on forever.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find the code at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Zubieta/Shine_On_You_Crazy_Fractal&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GitHub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>